Bruno Ribeiro

EDS CAD Engineer at Jaguar

brunoantunes28@gmail.com

Summary

Started my professional career as an equipment designer in Yazaki, and at the moment I'm working at Jaguar Land Rover as a Resident Engineer. I have 2 years of experience in designing equipment using Solidworks. Since I started working with JLR, things are a bit different, this is because the Job is more completed such as bringing 3D designs to reality and being more present on the field.

I'm always looking forward for new experience and willing to learn.

I face everything with ambitious.

I'm willing to teach my knowledge to who needs.

Enjoy team work and working on big projects.

I'm simple and have a lot to learn as to show others my knowledge.

Experience

EDS CAD Engineer at Yazaki Saltano

June 2014 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Resident Engineer at Jaguar Land Rover Engineering Centre, based in Gaydon site, being responsible for Designing and Developing Electrical Wire Harness.

- -3D/2D EDS CAD design and EDS CAD studies,
- -Business meetings with customers in order to arrange agreements, costing's and build support,
- -Designing harness as per customer Requirements,
- -Designing harness according to Yazaki Guidelines (DFM Design For Manufacturing)
- -Support customer vehicle build in Halewood,
- -Support Yazaki Manufacturing plant in Morocco (YMK Yazaki Morocco Kenitra)
- Advice on project / design issues,

Equiment Engineering at Yazaki Saltano

February 2012 - June 2014 (2 years 5 months)

Designing equipment for the assembly lines to help producing wire harnesses.

- -Components is designed using Solidworks and following a guideline
- -These components has to have poke yoki so that the operators don't assemble the wrong part numbers to the harnesses.
- -Orientate work orders between our supplier's and our manufacturing Plant's.
- -Validating our drawings with a fiscal and full functional sample. The intention of validating these drawings and samples is so that all our suppliers and Plants use one drawing for each component requested.

- -Upload drawings to our internal database.
- -Supporting Plant and Suppliers during manufacturing and validation process.

Languages

Portuguese,

Ingles

Skills & Expertise

Photoshop

Microsoft Office

Illustrator

Windows

English

Graphic Design

InDesign

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Illustration

Photography

Strategic Planning

Adobe Creative Suite

Art Direction

Solidworks

Team Leadership

Manufacturing

CAD

Product Design

Adobe Photoshop

SolidWorks

CATIA

Teamcenter

Indústria manufatureira

Education

Jaguar Land Rover

C3PNG for CAD Authors, 2014 - 2014

RoSPA - YEL-C

2014 - 2014

CADTECH

Technical, CATIA V5, 2012 - 2012

ESAD

Licenciatura design industrial, Industrial and Product Design, 2008 - 2012

Grade: Degree

Escola de Negocios, Vila Nova de Gaia
C.A.P, Initial Teacher Training, 2011 - 2011
Instituto Superior de Engenheira do Porto
Master's degree, Mechanical Engineering, 2012
Grade: Did not Finish
Volunteer Experience
Volunteer at Bombeiros Voluntarios ds Carvalhos 2009 - Present
-Volunteer Firefighter
Courses
Technical, CATIA V5
CADTECH
CATIA V5
EDS CAD Engineer
Yazaki Saltano
Teamcenter
Independent Coursework

RoSPA Driving Course

Bruno Ribeiro

EDS CAD Engineer at Jaguar

brunoantunes28@gmail.com



2 person has recommended Bruno

"I had the pleasure of working with Bruno Ribeiro at Yazaki Corporation for the last 3 years. He is an excellent professional, with great motivation and always eager to learn. Bruno is also helpful, supportive and an optimistic person that works well under pressure. I have no hesitations in recommending him and wish him the very best for the future."

— Florindo Sousa, Design Engineer, Jaguar Land Rover / Yazaki, worked directly with Bruno at Yazaki Saltano

"O Bruno Ribeiro é uma pessoa proactiva e com um grande sentido de responsabilidade. Tive a oportunidade de fazer uma formação com ele e demonstrou sempre ter capacidade de liderar equipas de uma maneira muito própria, criando um ambiente aberto e informal dando oportunidade a todos os colegas de demonstrarem o melhor de si. Demonstrou otimismo e uma excelente capacidade de ultrapassar obstáculos e motivar os outros a fazerem o mesmo. Além disso, a boa disposição que tem contagia as pessoas em seu redor, estando sempre disposto a ouvir e a evoluir a todos os níveis. Dedicado, organizado e perspicaz são as qualidades que fazem do Bruno Ribeiro uma mais-valia para qualquer grupo de trabalho."

— Patrícia Moreira, worked with Bruno at Yazaki Saltano

Contact Bruno on LinkedIn